Abdalah Amadou Gueye

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Portoflio

in LinkedIn Github



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience, holding a master degree in Applied Computer Science. I build high-performance web applications used by diverse user bases, using React, Next.js, Tailwind, with a strong focus on clean architecture, UI/UX, and modern development workflows.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, SMAL GMBH

• Developed and maintained reusable Ul components with React, Next.js, and **TypeScript**

- Developed reusable components contributing to a shared design system across
- Worked closely with backend engineers to integrate APIs and improve data flow between frontend and backend
- Collaborated on customer-facing features for high-traffic, Accessibility, Lighthouse

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, WORKING STUDENT, FUTURE STORIES

• Maintained and updated the company's Shopify-based website using Liquid and iQuery.

- Built custom Shopify apps using React.js to enhance e-commerce functionality.
- Contributed to Ul improvements and optimized code for performance.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, INTERN, OBERTYS

• Developed banking web applications using React.

- Integrated RESTful APIs to enable seamless communication between frontend and backend systems.
- Participated in agile development sprints and supported testing and documentation efforts.

01/2023 - Present

MUNICH, GERMANY

12/2021 - 11/2022 HAMBURG, GERMANY

> 01/2020 - 06/2020 DAKAR, SENEGAL

EDUCATION

Master in Applied Computer Science,

SRH HEIDELBERG UNIVERSITY - MASTER DEGREE

• Specialised in Usability Engineering, UI/UX Design

Bachelor in Computer Engineering, HASAN KALYONCU UNIVERSITY, BACHELOR DEGREE 2016 - 2020

2021 - 2023

HEIDELBERG, GERMANY

SKILLS

Frontend

React, Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Tailwind, HTML 5, SCSS,

Services / Tools

Vercel, Figma, Contentful

Backend / DevOps

Node JS, Express JS, GraphQL, MySQL, Supabase, Git, Vercel, Docker, AWS

Languages

English (Fluent), French (Fluent), Turkish (Intermediate), German (A2)